A Guide to the René Jules Dubos papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA122
Rockefeller Archive Center
- untitled, Negatives 5 × 7, 4 × 5, 2 × 2, 2½ inch, [GL 7/86]
  Some in color and some are glass negatives. in 2 5x7 negative boxes.
  Includes: -2½" [From Wooden Box in R.J. Dubos' office]. Used in book publications and articles?.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by subject/person.
  - Bacteria and Protozoa (Box 61, Folder 1)
    [See also: Bacterial Phage and Viruses].
    - 1960, 5 × 7 negatives; 1 item
    - 1962, 5 × 7 negatives; 9 items
  - Bacterial Phage and Viruses (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - 1959, 5 × 7 negatives; 2 items
    - 1962, 5 × 7 negatives; 3 items
  - Epidemiology and Tuberculosis (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - 1948, 5 × 7 negatives; 3 items
    - 1951, 5 × 7 negatives; 8 items
    - 1966, 5 × 7 negatives; 1 item
    - 1960, 4 × 5 negatives; 2 items
    - undated, 4 × 5 negatives; 1 in color
  - Fungus Colonies (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - 1960, 5 × 7 negatives; 3 items
    - 1962, 5 × 7 negatives; 8 items
    - undated, 4 × 5 negatives; 2 items
    - undated, 2 × 2 negatives; 2 items
  - Gericault, 1961; 5 × 7 neg # 61-1585B (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - History of Science and Medicine (Box 61, Folder 6)
    [See also: Pasteur and Portraits of Scientists in Box 61 and 62].
  - Pasteur (1), 1959; 5 1959 5 × 7 negs (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Pasteur (2), 5 × 7 negatives (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - 1950, 4 items
    - 1959, 1 item
    - undated, 1 item
  - Pictures by Fleming, undated; 2½ inch [GL 7/86] (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Portraits of Scientists (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - untitled, 12 5 × 7 negatives identified
    - untitled, 6 5 × 7 negatives not identified
      Includes:
      1 of Lister.
      1 of Freud.
      Bacon (or Harvey).
      1 of Vesali.
      4 of Koch.
      2 of Leeuwenhoek.
      Hippocrates.
      1 of Descartes.
      1 of B. Franklin.
      Tyndall.
      Fontenelle.
      Huxley.
      1 of H.G. Wells.
  - Psychiatry in Art, 5 × 7 negatives (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - 1961, 16 items
    - 1963, 1 item
    - undated, 3 items
  - Titration of Protective Action of Enzyme Against Infection. With Pneumococcus Type III, 1 3 × 4 GLASS SLIDE (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Tubercle bacilli (1), 1948 February 11; 1 5 × 7 GLASS NEG # 154-7 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Tubercle bacilli (1), 1950 January; 1 6 5 × 7 neg # 1408-7 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Tubercle bacilli (2), 1948 February 11; 1 5 × 7 GLASS NEG # 159-7 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Tubercle bacilli (2), 1948 February 11; 1 5 × 7 GLASS NEG # 160-7 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Tubercle bacilli (2), 1948 February 11; 1 5 × 7 GLASS SLIDE # 157-7 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Tubercle bacilli (2), 1948 April; 1 20 5 × 7 GLASS SLIDE # 941-7A (Box 62, Folder 10)
- Negatives, prints and original drawings mostly from JEM on "Lasting biological effects of early influences", in 5 × 7 negative/print envelopes, 5" letter GL 7/86 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  Includes data on TB.
  - Avery, O.T. Print of "from Al Coburn" marked on back. Taken in Nashville, Tenn?, 1
  - Hippocrates. Prints of. From D.W. Richards, Columbia University, 2
  - Unidentified person, at microscope. 1966 copy negative #66-1148, 3
  - Gramicidin. Print of. B-31242 X225 and Photocopy of "Crystals of Gramicidin. Isolation by Gramicidin from Tyrothricin was done by Drs. Hotchkiss and Dubos in 1940, substantially expanded antibiotic concepts", 4
  - Tyrocidine prints [MAG P], In triplicate, 5
  - Campus view showing South Lab, (RU), now Bronk Lab where Dr. Dubos' lab located on 4th floor. Negative #1031-6E (4x5), 1959 May 18; 6
- Negatives/prints for publications: (# of negs)
  - Negative # 60-1194A (1), 1960; 7 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negative #61-499C (2), 1961; 8 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negative #61559A and B (2), 1961; 9 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negatives #6258A-F (6), 1962; 10 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negative #62-591 (1), 1962; 11 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negatives #62-772A and B (2), 1962; 12 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negatives #62-0828A and B (2). Also prints, 1963; 13 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Negatives #63-0854 A, C, G, H (4), 1963; 14 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Negatives #64-2907 (2). Also prints, 1964; 15 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Negative #64-3288 (1), 1964; 16 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Negatives #64-3332 (4), 1964; 17 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Copy negatives #64-3350 from color lantern slides [LS] (2). Also prints, 1964; 18 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Negatives #64-3372 (2). Also prints, 1964; 19 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Negatives #64-1067 (2), 1964; 20 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Prints of negatives #65-2076, 1965; 21 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Negative #65-3743 (1), 1965; 22 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Negative #65-4108 (1), 1965; 23 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Negatives #66-0779 (2), 1966; 24 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Prints only from negatives #66-102. Dubos et al. Indigenous Flora, 1966; 25 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Negative #66-1131 (1), 1966; 26 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Negatives #66-2024 (3). Also prints, 1966; 27 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Negatives #66-2046 (1), 1966; 28 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Print only of negative #67-170, 1967; 29 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Negative #67-1288 (1), 1967; 30 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Negatives #67-816 (2), 1967; 31 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Negative #67-4226 (1), 1967; 32 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Negatives #67-4321 (7). Also prints, 1967; 33 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Figures for Dubos Paper I. JEM, April, vol 127, no. 9. 2 negatives of fig. 1. Also prints of figures 1-8, 34 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - 1 negative and also prints of. Lee, Chi-Jen and Dubos, René, 'early environmental influences' JEM 130, no 5 (1970), 35 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 5 negatives, also prints. Dubos, René, Lee, Chi-Jen and Costello, Richard, 'lasting biological effects' JEM 130, no 5, 1970, 36 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 3 negatives Also prints. Lee, Chi-Jen and Dubos, René, 'environmental influences VI'. JEM 133, no. 1, 1971, 37 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 1 negative Also prints. Prints from Dwayne's No. 2 JEM paper. [note on original negative envelope], 38 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 2 negatives Unidentified, except on negative re white women, 39 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 1 negative, 40 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    Also prints. Description at bottom of print:.
    Left: Caecum of germ free mouse (19% of total body Weight).
    Right: Caecum of conventional mouse (1. 6% of total body weight).
    Middle: Caecum of germ free mouse reassociated with lactobacilli and other bacilli (4. 5% of total weight). Picture taken in collaboration with Mr. Dennis Baker of Carworth Laboratories, New York City, New York.
  - Prints. Unidentified, 41 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Prints. Unidentified. Person's name on each (subject?), 42 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Print only. Germfree Mouse - Conventional Mouse - Female Age: 20 weeks. Fed on L-462 Diet, 43 (Box 63, Folder 6)
- Fleming, Sir Alex (1 year before Fleming's death) and Lady Fleming, wearing orchid, other 2 persons unidentified sitting at table., 1954 May 20; photographic print (Box 63, Folder 7)
- Prints for TB papers (Box 63, Folder 8)
  Some are mounted. Also includes data.
- Photographic prints for JEM, Vol 122, no 1 papers (1965?) (Box 63, Folder 9)
  Includes: Russell W. Schaedler, René Dubos, Richard Costello, Bacterial flora. Print of fig 1, paper 1.
  R. Dubos, R.W. Schaedler, R. Costello, and P. Hoet, Indigenous, normal, and autochthonous flora. Print of fig 1 for paper 2.
  Russell W. Schaedler, René Dubos, Richard Costello, Germfree mice and bacteria. Print of figure 1 for paper 3.
- Original drawings, prints, negatives of tables and figures for 1965? JEM paper (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Original drawings (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Page proof sheet of figures dated April 6, 1965, 1965 April 6 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Illustration sheets of tables and figures. Figures appear on page proof sheet (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Negatives/prints
    - 1 negative #2884-7C, 1951; 1
    - 3 negatives #63-0854, 1963; 2
    - 4 negatives #64-3288. Also prints, 1964; 3
    - Assorted prints, 4
  - Original drawings and prints (Box 63, Folder 11)
    Lee et al (Dubos) mouse intestinal flora. JEM 133, no 2, 1971?.
  - Original drawing, negatives and prints, 1968? (Box 63, Folder 12)
    Egilde Seravalli and René Dubos. Neonatal contamination and weight depression. JEM 127, no 4.
    Includes 11 5x7 negatives.
- Reprints by Dubos et al, and by others [who were in Dr. Dubos' dept, as per Jean Dubos], 1926-1982 1985; In 7 5" letter size boxes, [GL 8/86]
  - Reprints, 1926-1939
    - 1926 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 1927 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - 1928 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - 1929 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - 1930 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - 1931 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - 1932 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - 1934 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - 1935 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - 1936 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - 1937 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - 1938 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - 1939 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Reprints, 1940-1949
    - 1940 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 1941 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - 1942 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 1943 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 1944 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 1945 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 1946 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - 1947 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - 1948 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - 1949 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Reprints, 1950-1955
    - 1950 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - 1951 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - 1952 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - 1953 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - 1954 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - 1955 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - 1956-1964
    - Reprints, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - 1957 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - 1958 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - 1959 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - 1960 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - 1961 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - 1962 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - 1963 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - 1964 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Reprints, 1965-1970
    - 1965 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - 1966 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 1967 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - 1968 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - 1969 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 1970 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Reprints, 1971-1978
    - 1971 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - 1972 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - 1973 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - 1974 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - 1975 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Reprint of Lecture. "The Diseases of Civilization", 1975 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - 1976 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - 1977 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - 1978 (Box 69, Folder 9)
- Reprints and reprints by others [who were in the Dubos department. (As per J.D. (Jean Dubos))], 1979-1983 1985
  - 1979 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - 1980 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - 1981 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - 1982 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - 1983 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Reprint of 1978 lecture, "Adapting Man Adapting: Curing, Helping, Consoling" (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Reprints by others in the Dubos department (Box 70, Folder 7)
- Alphabetical reprint and clipping file by others. In rough alphabetical order. In 3-5" letter size boxes
  - "A"-"F", [GL 8/86.]
    - "A" (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - "B" (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - "C" (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - "D" (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - "E" (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - "F" (1) (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - "F" (2) (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - "G"-"M", [GL 8/86]
    - "G" (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - "H" (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - "J-K" (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - "L" (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - "McDermott, Walsh" (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - "M" (1) (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - "M" (2) (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - "N"-"W", [GL 8/86]
    - "N" (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - "P" (1) (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - "P" (2) (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - "R" (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - "S" (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - "T" (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - "W" (Box 73, Folder 7)
- Reprints by others, 2 boxes: 1 5" letter and 1 2½" letter size
  Arrangement in rough alphabetical order.
  - "A"-"H", [GL 8/86]
    - "A" (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - "B" (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - "C" (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - "D" (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - "H" (1) (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - "H" (2) (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - "I"-"Z", [GL 8/86]
    - "I" (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - "L" (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - "M" (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - "P", "Q", "R" (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - "S" (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - "W" (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - "Z" (Box 75, Folder 7)
- untitled, 2 boxes, Orange catalog card boxes containing 3 × 5 index cards of references
  - A - Z, 5" [GL 8/86] (Box 76)
  - A - Z Miscellaneous, 5" [GL 8/86] (Box 77)
    - Bibliography for "Reason Awake" A - Z. 5 cards marked "Seen but not used"
    - untitled, 3 boxes, 5 × 8 index cards of references
- Literature notes, background, photos with 5" negatives for book on Pasteur and on TB, [GL 8/86]
  Includes 1 glass negative and Kodachrome transparency. Also includes 5x8 reference cards:.
  - Photographs of Pasteur and his family. [Identification on photograph] (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of others (Box 78, Folder 2)
    Includes teachers, patron, friend of Pasteur. [Identification on photograph.].
  - 5x7 negatives, transparency, glass slide of Pasteur, C. Choppuis and laboratory glass equipment. [Identification on negative envelope] (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Book reviews of Dubos, "Louis Pasteur, Free Lance of Science" (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Postcards and prints re Pasteur and Pasteur's handwritten testament, signed, and dated Paris, March 29, 1977 and Arbois, August 25, 1980 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Printed background material re Pasteur (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Literature notes (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Pasteur and TB, 2 folders (Folder 1, Folder 2); 5 × 8 reference cards (Box 78, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence, 1964 1972; 2 items (Box 78, Folder 10)
    re loan of material re Pasteur.
- References, 5x8 index cards in 2 boxes
  - A - Mc, 8" (Box 79)
  - M - Z, 8" (Box 80)
- Chemical samples in glass bottles, In 2 2x2 slide boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to the original item.
  - Chemical samples in glass bottles, 6" (Box 81)
  - Chemical samples in glass bottles, 6" (Box 82)
- Chemical samples in glass bottles, In 2 3x4 slide boxes
  - Chemical samples in glass bottles, 4" (Box 83)
  - Chemical samples in glass bottles, 4" (Box 84)
  - Chemical samples in glass bottles, 2½" 2 letter (Box 85)
- Miscellaneous materials, galley proofs and notes, 5" letter
  - Memorabilia (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Bronze Plaque, "1959 Rio de Janiero, Congresso Internacional Sobra A Doenca De Chagas - [Carlos] De Sua Descoberta" (Inscription on plaque)
    - Printed invitation from Vice-President and Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller to Dr. and Mrs. Dubos to a "housewarming", 1975 September 24
    - Invitation from Dr. and Mrs. Joshua Lederberg to a reception honoring members of RU faculty, 1981 November 5
    - Undated. Prints of RU Campus looking toward New York Hospital. [From Jean Dubos], 1982 November 3
    - Printed material re Claude Bernard
    - Family tree [From M.W. Chase, 27 May 1982]
  - Correspondence (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Helen L. Carlock/Judy Schwartz re René J. Dubos contributions to Encyclopaedia Britannica in 1968 and 1974 w/attached New York Times, 1974 February 19
    - Israel Shenker, "Encyclopaedia Britannica Plans Major Change in 200 Years", 1974 January 11; Photocopies
    - [?], P&S, Columbia University, Dept of Medicine/Dubos. In French, 1977 October 13
    - Cathy Rogers/Carolyn Kopp, re clippings on Dubos from RU Public Information office, 1982 May 6
  - Reprints and clippings of articles by Dubos. Dated (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Reprints and clippings of articles by Dubos. Undated (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Advertisements for 2 of Dubos published books (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Programs/announcement. Dated and undated. Citing Dubos presentations/involvement (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous items. Dated and undated. [Some notations by J.D. (Jean Dubos)] (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Galley proofs and notes (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Galleys of Dubos mss (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Proofs of Dubos mss (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - notes on tulip breaking by Frank P. McWhorter, 1957 (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - notes, circa 1958 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - notes, 1959 (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Notes and mss. Undated (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - Quotes and notes, dated and undated; Also partial typescript (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - Note cards and notes on reading (Box 86, Folder 15)
- Unidentified book mss and other mss by Dubos. [From scrap drawers in René J. Dubos's office desk], 2½" letter
  - Dubos book. Photocopies of, [From drawer 1 of 4]
    - untitled, pp 1-130 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - untitled, pp 131-330 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified book ms by Dubos. Photocopies of, [From scrap drawer 4 of 4] (Box 87, Folder 3)
- Special collection of published articles by others in the form of reprints and photocopies of reprints, and photocopies of published books by others, 5" letter
  Also includes a collection of Dubos mss and mss by others for a proposed book on land ethics. Includes:.
  - Published mss by others. [Appears to be a special collection by Dubos] (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Reprints and photocopies of reprints (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Blanchet, Emile. Automobilism et Médecine. Role Therapeutique de l'Automobile", 1904; Photocopy (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Bulger, Roger J. Narcissus, Pogo and Lew Thomas' Wager, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Cassidy, Harold G. and Ross, Norman P. PROSPECTUS for a Film Series: "On the Nature of Knowledge". Designed for Initial Presentation on Public Television, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Cousins, Norman. Laymen and Medical Technology, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Cousins, Norman. Internship: Preparation or Hazing?, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Fox, Sidney W. Life from an Orderly Cosmos, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Grnek, Mirko Drazen. Evolution des Conceptions de Claude Bernard Sur le Milieu Intérieur, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Gubner, Richard S. Idle Mind and Body: The Workshop of Disease, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Hamburgh, Max. Is the Holocaust Relevant to Sociobiology?, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Hamburgh, Max. The Paradox of Human Goodness, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Humphrey, Nicholas. The Bronowski Memorial Lecture 'Four Minutes to Midnight', 1981 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Morison, Robert S. Science and Social Attitudes, 1969 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Neel, James V. Lessons from a "Primitive" People, 1970; Photocopy (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Richards, Dickinson W. Homeostasis Versus Hyperexis: or Saint George and the Dragon, 1953 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Richards, Dickinson W. Homeostasis: Its Dislocations and Perturbations, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Thomas, Lewis. Future Prospects for Basic Science, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Tubiana, Maurice. Un Scientifique Devant les Realites et les Mythes Contemporains. Date? (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - [Author?]. "In Praise of the Common Man", Photocopies. 100 pp. (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Hofer, Myron A., "The Roots of of Human Behavior", 2 folders
    Photocopies of.
    - untitled, pp 1-156 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - untitled, pp 157-331 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - [Author?]. "Antimythe", 155 pp of photocopies (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Material re proposed book on land ethics
    Includes mss by Dubos and others. In 2 folders:.
    - Mss re proposed book on land ethics with Dubos mss and mss by others, Photocopies (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Mss by others, continued for proposed book on land ethics, Photocopies (Box 88, Folder 7)
- Photographic prints, negatives, some art work and a glass slide primarily for Dubos, "The Unseen World"
  Includes photographs/negatives for other Dubos published books. In 2-2½" letter size boxes:.
  - Photographs/negatives. Scientists and others. Identified (1), [GL 8/86] (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Photographs/negatives. Scientists and others. Identified (2) (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Scientific photographs/negatives and glass slide. Identified (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Photographs/negatives. Scientific equipment. Identified, [GL 8/86] (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Scientific photographs/negatives. Unidentified (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Photographs/negatives. Miscellaneous. Identified (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten identifications of illustrations of Dubos, "The Unseen World" (by RU Press?) (Box 90, Folder 4)
    [See also: Dubos Oversize box of photographs].
- Audio tapes, 2½" letter [GL 8/86.] (Box 91)
  RAC is unable to provide access to the original item, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - René Dubos. The Stock Market Observer, 1969 June 12
    WOR - TV telecast.
    1 R/R (Reel to Reel) tape.
    [See letter enclosed: 1969 June 18, Edward A. Warren/Dubos, re audio tape and Dubos appearance and comments on the Stock Market Observer program].
  - Leakey Foundation Lecture. Dubos, "Improving on Nature", 1977 February 1; 1 video cassette.
  - Channel 13. Bill Moyers Journal. "René Dubos", 1980 February 20; 1 video cassette 3/4" #018549. [Professional Format VCR]
  - J. Bronowski recorded at Center for Study of Den. Inst, Year?, November 3; 1 American Recording Tape. Track I, 3-3/4 speed, 120 minutes.
- Dr. and Mrs. Dubos personal items (Box 92)
  In June 1980 Dr. and Mrs. Dubos sent to the Archives a large group of personal items which included numerous citations; citations with the Honorary Degree Diploma; citations on memberships and prizes and also the statuette presented with the Lasker Award. These have been packed in storage boxes — each box has its own contents lists as well as the listing of the Register. A few items, too large for the storage boxes have been packed in packages.
  - D Sc Loyola University 1970 Honorary Fellowship 1965, Institute of Medicine Chicago, 1970 1965
  - D Sc Catholic University, 1972
  - D Sc St. Johns University 1968 Honorary Life Membership 1973, New York Academy of Science
  - D Sc Beloit College, 1968
  - D Sc Fairfield College 1973 Louis J. Hirschman Memorial Lect. 1966, American Procologic Society
  - D Sc Wesleyan University, 1967
  - D Sc New School of Social Research "Microflora of the gastrointestinal tract", 1956
  - D Sc University of Guelph, 1979
    - Certificate of Advanced Medical Studies American Soc. of Contemporary Medicine and Surgery, 1975-1976
    - Passano Award, 1960
    - Jesse and John Davy Professor, 1978
      Certificate of appreciation 1978 University of Washington.
  - Doctor Humane Letters Carleton College, 1966
  - Doctor (Honoris Causa) University of Calgary, 1972
  - Doctor of Laws Montclair College, 1975
  - Doctor Humane Letters Williams College, 1971
  - Doctor of Humane Letters Kalamazoo College, 1971
  - LL D Colby College, 1966
    [Mark Dreessen supplied information re LL D Colby College].
  - Doctor of Literature Thomas Jefferson University, 1974
  - Doctor of Humane Letters Marietta College, 1978
  - Doctor of Humanities Assumption College, 1974
- MEMORABILIA (Box 93)
  - La Salle College Centennial Award, 1963
  - Lasker Award - American Public Health Association, 1948
  - D Sc. Marquette University, 1971
  - Honorary Member Salerni Collegium, University of Southern Calif. School of Medicine, 1965
  - Kober Lecture, 1961
  - Distinguished World Member International House, 1971
  - Magister Emeritus Brazilian Section, Institute for Mind Power Development and Psychosomatic Research, 1976
  - ASPO Medal Award Citation, 1972
  - Arches of Science Award (folder of material), 1966
  - Robert Koch Medal — Citation, 1960
  - Pulitzer Prize Citation, 1969
  - Mead Johnson Award for Research in Pediatrics, 1940
  - Doctor of Law, Alberta College, 1963
  - D Sc. Bard College, 1971
  - Citation on election as Colleague of the Cathedral Church, 1975
  - NIH Jules Freund Memorial Seminar, 1965
  - Associate Fellow New York Academy of Medicine, 1947
  - Societas Medicus Polonorum, 1970
  - Doctor of Medicine University of Sherbrooke, 1969
  - Doctor of Humane Letters Marietta College, 1978
  - Member National Academy of Science, 1941
  - D Sc. University of Rochester, 1941
- MEMORABILIA (Box 94)
  - Doctor of Laws University of California, 1965
  - D Sc. Harvard University, 1942